As the saying goes, ‘time waits for no man’.
常言道，“岁月不待人”。
Time is always against us, and we just can’t stop it.
时间总在与我们作对，而我们对此束手无策。
Maybe that’s why some of us are always running late for appointments.
或许这就是有些人赴约总迟到的原因。
But if timekeeping is not what you’re good at, don’t stress. There might be a good reason for your lack of punctuality.
但如果你不擅长守时，不必焦虑，你缺乏准时性或许是有充分理由的。
People’s attitudes to being on time vary.
人们对待守时的态度各不相同。
Some clock-watch and make sure they’re bang on time for a meeting.
有些人总盯着时钟，确保开会准时到场。
It is, after all, rude to be late, and if you can make it on time, why can’t everyone else?
毕竟，迟到是不礼貌的行为，既然你能准时，其他人为什么不能呢？
But if, like me, you want to make every second count, you might try to squeeze as much as you can into the time you have available.
但如果你和我一样，想让每一秒都过得有意义，就可能会试图在有限的时间里塞进尽可能多的事情。
However, when your schedule doesn’t run to plan, your punctuality inevitably slips.
然而，当你的日程安排未能按计划进行时，你就难免会变得不守时。
People who lack promptness have been described as ‘time benders’.
那些做事拖沓的人被称为“时间拖延者”。
Author Grace Pacie told the BBC that “they’re the people who don’t want to be late, but they have a strange resistance to being early, and they don’t allow enough time.”
作家格雷丝·帕西在接受BBC采访时表示：“这类人其实不想迟到，但他们就是莫名抗拒早到，而且预留的出行时间总是不够。”
They assume their journey to an appointment will always go smoothly, and the train will always be on time!
他们想当然地认为，赴约路上一定会一帆风顺，火车也总会准点到站。
Perceptions of unpunctual people are almost always negative – even if sometimes wrong.
人们对不守时者的看法几乎都是负面的——即便有时这种看法并不准确。
Writing for the BBC, Laura Clarke says: “Being consistently late might not be your fault. It could be your type.
劳拉·克拉克在为BBC撰写的文章中称：“总是迟到或许不是你的错，可能是性格使然。
The punctually-challenged often share personality characteristics, such as optimism, low levels of self-control, anxiety, or a penchant for thrill-seeking, experts say.
专家表示，不守时的人往往有着相似的性格特质，比如乐观、自控力差、容易焦虑或是喜欢寻求刺激。
It is also possible people are late so not to be conspicuous and to avoid the anxious wait for others to turn up.
还有一种可能是，人们迟到是为了避免过于引人注目，同时也不想焦灼地等待他人到来。
Maybe us latecomers should make more of an effort and follow the advice I heard to not ‘try’ to be on time but ‘decide’ to be on time.
或许我们这些迟到星人应该再努努力，遵循我听过的一条建议：不要“试着”准时，而是“下定决心”准时。
But I know if a meeting or a deadline really matters, then I’ll be there.
不过我心里清楚，要是某个会议或截止日期真的很重要，我肯定会准时到场。
Otherwise relax, even if others are cursing you!
至于其他情况，就放宽心吧，即便别人在心里咒骂你也没关系！